## Tanmay Shankar

E-mail: tanmay.shankar@gmail.com Web: <a href="http://tanmayshankar.weebly.com">http://tanmayshankar.weebly.com</a> Github: <a href="https://github.com/tanmayshankar">https://github.com/tanmayshankar</a>

RESEARCH INTERESTS I am interested in enabling robots to learn and reason about skills and abstractions, and how to use them to solve complex tasks. To that end, I am interested in discovering insights that bridge unsupervised machine learning, reinforcement and imitation learning and classical robotics.

**EDUCATION** 

#### Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, USA.

2020 - Present

Ph.D. in Robotics, Robotics Institute.

Thesis Advisor: Jean Oh, Robotics Institute.

#### Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, USA.

2016 - 2018

Masters in Robotics, Robotics Institute.

Thesis Advisors: Katharina Muelling & Kris Kitani, Robotics Institute.

#### Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati, Guwahati, India.

2012 - 2016

B. Tech., Mechanical Engineering, minor in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Work Experience

#### Facebook AI Research, Pittsburgh, USA

2018 - 2020

Research Engineer, working with Abhinav Gupta and Shubham Tulsiani.

#### Facebook AI Research, Pittsburgh, USA

2022 - 2022

Research Intern, working with Stuart Anderson, Aravind Rajeswaran, Vikash Kumar.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Learning Unsupervised Skill Correspondences Across Robots

[Website]

Advisor: Jean Oh

Ph.D. Research Project, CMU

Translating Robot Skills via Unsupervised Representation Alignment

- Formulated unsupervised approach to translate skills across different morphological robots, inspired by unsupervised machine translation.
- Transferred skills and task-strategies across robots using unsupervised translation.

#### Learning Robot Skills with Temporal Variational Inference

[Website]

Research Project, FAIR

Advisor: Abhinav Gupta

Unsupervised Hierarchical Policy Learning from Demonstrations

- Formulated an unsupervised temporal variational inference to learn hierarchical policies (options, represented as latent variables) from demonstrations, using ideas of consistency.
- Applied our unsupervised objective to learn continuous spaces of options on 4 robotic datasets.

#### Discovering Motor Programs by Recomposing Demonstrations

[Website]

Research Project, FAIR

Advisors: Shubham Tulsiani & Abhinav Gupta

Unsupervised Skill Discovery from Robot Demonstrations by Recomposition

- Formulated an unsupervised loss to discover the space of motor primitives of a set of robot demonstrations, using ideas of recomposition, simplicity, parsimony, and plannability.
- Showed efficacy of primitives to accelerate downstream task learning on a Baxter robot.

# Learning Neural Parsers via Deterministic Differentiable Imitation Learning [Website]

Graduate Research Thesis, CMU

Advisors: Katharina Muelling & Kris Kitani

Learning to Parse via hybrid Imitation-Reinforcement Learning

- Introduced a novel Deterministic Policy Gradient DRAG, for the hybrid IL-RL setting, as a deterministic actor-critic variant of AggreVaTeD, or an imitation learning variant of DDPG.
- Applied DRAG to learn a neural parser by imitating an information-gain maximizing oracle.

#### Reinforcement Learning via Recurrent Convolutional Neural Networks [Website]

Bachelor's Thesis, IIT Guwahati Advisors: S. K. Dwivedy & Prithwijit Guha

Reinforcement Learning Networks - Fusing Learning and Planning

- Introduced a neural approximation to value iteration, by representing the expectation of the Bellman backup as convolutions, and iterations as temporal recurrence.
- Introduced the QMDP-RCNN, a learnable approximation to partially observable planning.

#### Publications

- T. Shankar, A. Gupta, "Learning Robot Skills with Temporal Variational Inference", International Conference on Machine Learning, ICML 2020. [PDF] [Code]
- T. Shankar, S. Tulsiani, L. Pinto, A. Gupta, "Discovering Motor Programs by Recomposing Demonstrations", International Conference on Learning Representations, ICLR 2020. [PDF]
- T. Shankar, N. Rhinehart, K. Muelling, K. Kitani, "Learning Neural Parsers with Deterministic Differentiable Imitation Learning", Conference on Robot Learning, CoRL 2018.
- T. Shankar, S.K. Dwivedy, P. Guha, "Reinforcement Learning via Recurrent Convolutional Neural Networks", International Conference on Pattern Recognition, ICPR 2016.
- T. Shankar, S.K. Dwivedy, "A Hybrid Assistive Wheelchair Exoskeleton", International Convention on Rehabilitation Engineering and Assistive Technology, i-CREATe 2015. [PDF]
- T. Shankar, A. Biswas, V. Arun, "Development of an Assistive Stereo Vision System", International Convention on Rehabilitation Engineering and Assistive Technology, i-CREATe 2015. [PDF]

#### Papers under REVIEW

T. Shankar, Y. Lin, A. Rajeswaran, V. Kumar, S. Anderson, J. Oh, "Translating Robot Skills: Learning Unsupervised Skill Correspondences Across Robots", under review at International Confer-

SERVICE	&	

ence on Machine Learning, ICML 2022.

Leadership

Reviewer for ICML 2022, ICLR 2020 & CVPR 2019. 2019 - 2022 Founded an AI and Robotics Research mentoring program for IITG Undergraduates. 2015 - 2016 Mentor for CMU Undergrad from underrepresented groups getting into AI Research. 2020

AWARDS

Samsung Innovation Award, for excellence in research, IIT Guwahati. 2015 Master R. Balakrishnan Memorial Award, Best All Rounder Student. 2011 Dr. Lt. Col. T S Kalvanam Award, for the Best Outgoing Student. 2011

2018

Teaching EXPERIENCE Teaching Assistant, Deep Reinforcement Learning, CMU Instructor: Dr. Ruslan Salakhutdinov, Machine Learning Department

OPEN SOURCE

github.com/facebookresearch/CausalSkillLearning, github.com/tanmayshankar/RCNN\_MDP

TECHNICAL SKILLS Languages Known: Python, Familiar with C / C++, Matlab.

> Software Packages: TensorFlow, PyTorch, OpenCV, PCL, MATLAB, LATEX, Rviz, Gazebo, ROS

Rethink Baxter & Sawyer, Odroid XU3, Pixhawk Autopilot. *Hardware*:

GRADUATE

Deep Learning Language Grounding to Vision and Control

Coursework Deep Reinforcement Learning Machine Learning

> Computer Vision Math Fundamentals for Robotics Kinematics Dynamics and Controls Probabilistic Graphical Models